# Nisha Kumari

# Senior UX Designer

- Valid Work Permit for the EU
- Berlin, Germany
- +4917675919268
- ▶ Portfolio
- Bē nisha-kumari-de
- in nisha-kumari-de



### **User Experience Design**

- User Experience Research (UXR)
- User Interviews
- Sketching & ideating
- Storytelling
- Usability Testing
- Heuristic Analysis

#### **User Interface Design**

- · Design System
- · Wire-framing
- Mockups
- Prototyping
- Accessibility

#### **Platform Expertise**

- Websites
- Web Apps & Dashboards
- SaaS
- Mobile Applications
- Human Machine Interface (HMI)

#### **Tools**

- Figma
- Miro
- Maze
- ProtoPie
- Notion
- Jira
- Confluence



Senior UX Designer with 6+ years of experience designing intuitive interfaces that enhance product efficiency and user satisfaction. Proven track record of success in SaaS, web, mobile, and Human Machine Interface (HMI) design. Strong communicator with a keen eye for design trends and technologies.



# Professional Experience

# **Royal Cyber Inc**

### **Senior UX Designer**

Feb 2023 - present | Berlin - Remote

- Led user research, design, and implementation for cloud security, Alpowered automation testing, and event management apps, elevating usability, and streamlining workflows.
- Collaborated with product managers and cross-functional teams to define design strategy, ideate, and create user-centric solutions that meet business goals.
- Developed and maintained design systems and style guides, ensuring consistency and scalability across products.

### 3DesignThinkers

#### Freelance UX Researcher

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023 | Berlin - Remote

- Led user research and redesign initiatives for an e-learning platform offering design and preparatory courses.
- Conducted comprehensive quantitative and qualitative research, such as heuristic analysis, A/B testing, and heat mapping to identify user needs and inform design decisions.

### **Wipro Limited**

### **Senior UX Designer**

Nov 2019 – Jul 2022 | Pune, India & Czech Republic

- Conducted in-depth user research to understand user behaviors and preferences, enabling the creation of low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototypes. These efforts significantly improved the HMI usability for Manufacturing Execution Systems (MES).
- Engaged in agile practices and scrum framework, fostering collaborative teamwork and efficient project execution.

### **Project Engineer**

Apr 2017 - Oct 2019 | Pune, India

• Developed REST clients for e-commerce web development and collaborated closely with the UX designers for seamless integration.



**English** (Proficient)

Hindi (Native)

**German** (Learning A1)



### **Education**

## **Google UX Design Specialization** Coursera

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022 Berlin, Germany

# **Bachelor's degree - Electronics** and Communications **Engineering ITM Gwalior**

2012 - 2016 | Gwalior, India ECE is a four-year AICTE-approved undergraduate program



## **Spektrum Akademie Zeitplaner**

- Crafted scheduling solutions, overcoming challenges in tracking progress and planning.
- Performed thorough user interviews and stakeholder consultations to grasp the challenges of admins, teachers, and students. Applied meticulous research and design, refining wireframes and high-fidelity designs iteratively for usability and accessibility.
- Delivered a transformative scheduling solution, surpassing traditional tools and enhancing collaboration.

## Mqtizer - Cross-Platform MQTT Client for Industrial-Grade IoT Solutions &

- Gathered valuable user feedback and conducted thorough usability tests, leading to user-driven enhancements and improved app functionality, enhancing user retention.
- Designed and optimized commercial website and marketing collateral for MQTIZER

# VisionarAI - AI for Visionaries ⊘ Secured 2nd place in the "soonami.io GmbH Cohort O Hackathon"

- Crafted intuitive user-centric experience for VisionarAI, utilizing insights from Y Combinator resources, aiding founders in product discovery.
- Collaborated with developers to simplify complex features for userfriendly interfaces and seamless interaction.